Well, I think that game is really starting to take shape.
We have our road that moves down constantly.
We have our car that we control, we have our obstacles that we have to avoid.
So our so now pretty good turn this morning tackle into obstacles have generating more traffic adding
in more cars.
So generally may be thinking to yourself well this is easy.
You can see if all is to do is duplicate the obstacle car the few times and Bob's your uncle.
Well, maybe your uncle, but that's not really the solution.
Well, let's give it a try, shall?
You know, as I say, the simplest solution is the best solution.
And this sure sounds simple.
So right clicking on our car then hitting duplicate.
And let's do that one more time.
There we go.
Now we have three cars ready to go.
Let's test this out.
Well, that's somewhat works, but our cars all appear at the same time, and sometimes in the same
lane.
So we could just go to these duplicated cars, add a wait statement to each of them at the top of the
script, and have it be one second and two seconds to have them evenly spaced and once again hitting
play.
Well, I got off to.
We got calls to start moving the bear.
You can actually see it works.
Uh, now, it was just.
If it all be like, so, well, then, like, why don't we joins the solution?
Let me introduce you to a little acronym which is called Dry code.
Dry code.
And what Dry stands for is don't repeat yourself.
Let me say it again.
Don't repeat yourself.
Haha, that's very funny.
Yeah, this is very popular saying in programming is often duplicating code.
Might sound like the easy solution.
However, when you start doing this, things can get really messy and it also makes things hard to maintain.
For instance, if I wanted to change the speed of my cars, I couldn't just go change it in one spot.
I would have to go into each sprite to change it.
So that being said, let's look for a smarter solution.
So firstly deleting all these duplicates, then going to our main obstacle sprite and finally going
to the control blocks.
You will see we have these blocks here.
When I start as a clone, create clone of and delete this clone.
And these are really important blocks.
So dragging them down and then down.
Let's have a look.
So let's test this out by bringing this create clone of myself inside of this if statement.
Then hitting play.
You'll see that each time our car reaches the end, a new clone appears at the top.
But you also see that these cars don't really move.
They just sort of stay there, which isn't really ideal.
Well, that, my friends, is what this block is for.
So basically what is happening is our script is playing.
And then when this condition is true, it creates a clone of itself, which is the obstacle call.
A clone is essentially an identical copy of a sprite, such as all the costumes.
It has, the sound effects, and more.
However, one key difference is that a clone isn't the same as duplicating a sprite, because as you
saw, the duplicated sprites move like the regular ones, while the clone just was stuck at the top.
That's because the clone doesn't have access to the script, because this script is only activated when
the flag is clicked, and that only happens once at the beginning.
So this is where this block comes in.
It allows us to add code to our cloned sprites.
So if we simply duplicate this code and add it to when I start as a clone, then hit play.
You will see that each time our characters reaches the end, a clone is added and has the same functionality.
But as you can also see, it really just doesn't stop cloning.
But I think you get the idea.
So now that you have a good understanding of the important concept of dry code and cloning, don't repeat
yourself.
Let's make this work.
Firstly, we can get rid of all the code in the code block, as we can also disconnect this code from
the when flag clicked button.
Now we can add a forever block and a wait block, and in this create a clone of myself block.
So basically every second will create a clone of itself.
Now for the important bit.
Let's drag this code here onto the when I start as a clone.
But remember, we can't keep it like this because it will just keep creating new clones.
Basically, what we can do is when the car reaches the end, we can delete this clone.
Well, let's test this out.
Once again, that's not quite right.
The cars just drive in a line.
And this makes sense, obviously, because if you look at the code every time the car starts at a clone,
it goes to zero x and 190 y.
So all we need to do is get rid of that and then move this go to random position to the start of the
script.
And once again, if we hit play well that works a lot better.
There are two small bugs we can fix.
Firstly, let's hide our main sprite so it doesn't stick to our screen and then show our cloned sprite.
Also we can change this.
Go to Y to a higher number like 250 which makes it look more seamless.
And there you go.
It's working properly now.
And if you follow along, that is absolutely amazing.
Work on completing this lesson.
We really covered some ground here, so well done.
So let's keep up this momentum and start bringing this game to life.